<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cezar Mathe</title><link>https://cezarmathe.com/</link><description>Recent content on Cezar Mathe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cezarmathe.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>https://cezarmathe.com/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cezarmathe.com/about/</guid><description>Hi, my name is Cezar, I&amp;rsquo;m 17 and I&amp;rsquo;m a student at the &amp;ldquo;Andrei Muresanu&amp;rdquo; National College in Dej, Cluj, Romania. I wrote my first line of code when I was 9 and I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying the experience since then.
Tinkering with my Linux system is one of my favourite things, along with writing Go code, Bash scripts and command line utilities.
Beyond my absolute favourite things, I participate in the First Tech Challenge program since season I and I can say that I&amp;rsquo;ve done any technical thing related to the robot: engineering, programming(in Java) and even piloting.</description></item><item><title>Creating an utility to help me maintain my online presence: part 1</title><link>https://cezarmathe.com/posts/2019-04-07-creating-an-utility-to-help-me-maintain-my-online-presence-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cezarmathe.com/posts/2019-04-07-creating-an-utility-to-help-me-maintain-my-online-presence-part-1/</guid><description>I really enjoy programming, so I write code quite often. Which means that my Portfolio section gets outdated quite quick.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I thought about creating a utility that automates the process of recording and processing my work, hence I came up with the name PWRP, which stands for Personal Work Recorder Processor. You can find this project here.
I decided to write this utility in Go because I love this programming language and it would be a very good opportunity for me to learn more about it.</description></item><item><title>Using Arduino pins as a data bus for transfering bits</title><link>https://cezarmathe.com/posts/2019-02-03-using-arduino-pins-as-a-data-bus-for-transfering-bits/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cezarmathe.com/posts/2019-02-03-using-arduino-pins-as-a-data-bus-for-transfering-bits/</guid><description>These days I came up with an idea for a really cool IoT project, but that requires using Arduino pins as a bus for writing bits, so I wrote a small library for doing exactly that.
There is a video which showcases an example usage:</description></item><item><title>How to manage your dotfiles like a boss</title><link>https://cezarmathe.com/posts/2019-01-09-how-to-manage-your-dotfiles-like-a-boss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cezarmathe.com/posts/2019-01-09-how-to-manage-your-dotfiles-like-a-boss/</guid><description>First, a little bit of background. You set up a new computer and chances are you haven&amp;rsquo;t backed up your dotfiles. What do you do now? You spend hours trying to replicate the workflow and configurations, because someone didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to back up his dotfiles. But hey, at least you&amp;rsquo;re trying now.
Before we start Go through your home directory, ~/.config and other folders that might contain configurations.</description></item><item><title>Getting myself a website</title><link>https://cezarmathe.com/posts/2019-01-03-getting-myself-a-website/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cezarmathe.com/posts/2019-01-03-getting-myself-a-website/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a brand new year and I have big plans so far. And one of them is getting an up-and-running website for myself. Here it is.</description></item><item><title>Contact me</title><link>https://cezarmathe.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cezarmathe.com/contact/</guid><description> You can contact me directly here: Email: cezarmathe@gmail.com LinkedIn: Cezar Mathe See my freelancer profiles here: Upwork: Cezar Mathe Freelancer: Cezar M. Visit one of my online profiles: GitHub: cezarmathe Medium: @cezarmathe Stackoverflow: Cezar Mathe Other links related to me:</description></item><item><title>My work</title><link>https://cezarmathe.com/portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cezarmathe.com/portfolio/</guid><description>Open source projects pwrp Personal Work Recorder-Processor
pinbitwriter An IoT library for writing bits to digital pins like they are a data transfer bus.
discord-message-embedder A discord bot that sends embedded messages for you by parsing a JSON string.
trackexpenses-android An application that helps you track your money.
gosh A primitive shell written in Go.
repotools A tool for easily managing Arch Linux meta packages and package repositories.</description></item></channel></rss>